Guide to the Fred Ross papers M0812
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Fred Ross papers
1920-2003
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Ross, Fred, 1910-1992
Ross, Fred, Jr.
M0812
25 Linear Feet (48 boxes; 1 map folder)
Fred W. Ross, Sr. was a pioneer community and labor organizer who fought racial prejudice and championed the rights of the working poor. His papers include correspondence, memoranda, subject files, press clippings, drafts, unpublished writing, photographs, and audio recordings.
Biographical / Historical
Fred W. Ross was born August 23, 1910 in San Francisco to Fred W. and Daisy C. Ross. He grew up in the Echo Park neighborhood of Los Angeles and attended Belmont High School until 1929. An English literature and social science major, he graduated from the University of Southern California in 1937.
Giving up his original plan to become a teacher because he could not find a job during the Depression, Ross became a caseworker with the state relief administration. In 1939 he became the manager of the Arvin Migratory Labor Camp near Bakersfield, the same camp John Steinbeck drew on to write The Grapes of Wrath. Ross encouraged the inhabitants to organize themselves. In 1941 he began to work for the War Relocation Authority helping Japanese American internees leave the camps and obtain jobs and housing.
In 1946 Ross went to work for the American Council on Race Relations to promote "Councils for Civic Unity" in California in response to the racial tensions that had surfaced during the war. The eight Hispanic Unity Leagues Ross organized fought segregation in schools and elsewhere. From 1947 to 1952 he worked for Saul Alinsky and the Industrial Areas Foundation. With their support Ross established the first Community Service Organization in the Boyle Heights area of Los Angeles. In 1952 he met Cesar Chavez, then a young man in San Jose, and hired him. Both men founded 22 CSO chapters throughout California in the 1950's. As a decades-long mentor, Ross had a strong influence on Chavez, who remembered that "as time went on, Fred became sort of my hero. I saw him organize and I wanted to learn."
In 1964 Ross was hired by the National Presbyterian Church to establish a community self-help group in Guadalupe, Arizona, a poor small town, populated by Yaqui Indians and Mexican Americans, where the church owned much property. The following year, 1965-66, Ross taught community organizing at Syracuse University in the first course of its kind. In 1966 Ross began his work with Cesar Chavez's UFW, training hundreds of organizers. He organized many well-known strikes and boycotts, among them the Giumarra strike of 1967, the grape boycott of 1968, the lettuce strikes of 1970 and 1973, and the Gallo wine boycott of 1973.
In 1978 Ross directed Jerry Brown's campaign for governor of California. Ross helped to organize the United Domestic Workers of America and the 1979 Chiquita Banana Boycott. In 1984 he became involved with Nuclear Freeze, Jobs with Peace, CISPES (Committee in Solidarity with the People of El Salvador). He also worked with the anti-interventionist group Neighbor to Neighbor with his son, Fred Ross, Jr.
Ross developed and taught organizing techniques such as the house meeting. This work is well-documented in the Papers. In 1989 Neighbor to Neighbor published Ross' Axioms for Organizers as a booklet. The same year, El Taller Grafico press (UFW) pubished Ross' first book, Conquering Goliath: Cesar Chavez at the Beginning.
In 1937 Ross married Yvonne Gregg; they divorced shortly after the birth of their son, Robert, in 1940. Ross married Frances Gibson in 1943, and they had three children, Julia, Fred, Jr., and Rob. Fred Ross died on September 27, 1992. He was inducted into the California Hall of Fame in 2014.
Scope and Contents
The Ross Papers comprise the personal and professional materials of Fred Ross and occupy approximately 25 linear feet.
The general condition of the papers reflects Ross' peripatetic lifestyle as an organizer. Before being acquired by Stanford, the Ross papers were stored in various locations; a few of the papers have extensive water and mold damage. Many of the files and papers are incomplete, break off suddenly, or have had to be reconstructed or reorganized. The general organization of the papers is also affected by the fact that Ross suffered from Alzheimer's disease at the end of his life. Often he went back and relabelled files, sometimes erroneously; when these errors were obvious, they were corrected in the folder title. In going through many of his files, Ross removed items to use for his autobiographical manuscripts and then did not replace them. This means that some files have obvious gaps. When the missing materials could clearly be identified, they were put back with the larger files to which they belonged. When the provenance of stray items could not be easily determined, they were filed by themselves or, when found in a group, filed together with other "missing pieces" under titles such as "misc. manuscript pages" or "organizing materials (without organization names)." Overall the processor followed the principle of preserving as much of the original order as possible and leaving it to the individual researcher to determine what may belong together.
The Manuscript and Audiotape Series may be the richest for researchers. It is here that Ross' organizing work and personal experience are most fully documented.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was purchased by Stanford University Libraries in 1995 and 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Audiovisual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy. Selected audio has been transferred.
Related Collections
Stanford also holds the Community Service Organization History Project records (M1669).
Another small collection of Ross' papers is held by the Archives of Labor and Urban Affairs at Wayne State University in Detroit. This collection includes daily field activity reports documenting Ross's training of Chavez as an organizer for the Community Service Organization from 1954 to 1965 and an untitled manuscript, written around 1973, about Chavez and his early work in the organization of farm workers.
Notable or frequently mentioned individuals (A-Z):
Missing Title
John Adler
Saul Alinsky
Dan Bacar
Bill Beachy
Jenny Brashear
Dave Burciaga
Cesar Chavez
Andy Coe
[Ellie] Cohen
Greg Costello
Joe Deety
Chris Donoughue
Joe Dukes
Nancy Elliot
Dianne Feinstein
Mike Ganley
Marshall Ganz
Warren Hagstrom
Bob Hardie
Chirs Hartmire
H. Hasawara
Hayes
Ralph Helstein
Dolores Huerta
Nick Jones
Dave Koeler
Ignacio ("Nacho") Lopez
Mark Lyons
Barbara Macry
David Martinez
Mary McCarthy
Blain McGowan
Eliseo Medina
Dolores Mendoza
Ray Mork
Henry Nava
Frank Ortiz
Bob Parcel
Lois Pryner
Clint Reilly
Tony Rios
John Rodrigo
Arturo Rodriguez
Edward R. Roybal
Hector Tarango
Jo M. Tobin
Ruth Tuck
Barbara Wyler
Notable institutions in the collection:
Missing Title
American Council on Race Relations (ACRR)
American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO)
Agricultural Workers Organizing Committee (AWOC)
California Federation for Civic Unity (CFCU)
Central America Peace Education Training Project
Community Action Training Center (CATC)
Community Service Organization (CSO)
Guadalupe Organization, Inc. (GO)
Industrial Areas Foundation
League of United Latin American Citizens (LULAC)
National Farm Worker Ministry
National Farm Workers' Association (NFWA)
National Farm Workers' Union (NFWU)
Neighborhood Service Organization (NSO)
Nuclear Weapons Freeze Campaign
State Relief Administration (SRA)
Survival Institute
International Brotherhood of Teamsters
United Farm Workers (UFW)
War Relocation Authority (WRA)
Agricultural laborers -- Labor unions -- Organizing; Community organization; Ross, Fred, 1910-1992; Ross, Fred, 1910-1992; Ross, Fred, Jr.
- Series A. Personal Materials (2 linear feet)
  Scope and Contents
  These boxes hold Ross' personal correspondence, certificates of appreciation, and material on his health and finances.
  - Cards (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Datebook, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Datebook, 1975-76 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Datebook, 1978-79 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Datebook, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Finances (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Fred Ross, Sr., Collection, Archives of Labor and Urban Affairs (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Harvard speech, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Job, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Maid, 1950's (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Medical (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Memorial service, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Poetry (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - References (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Voting Registration Report, Alameda (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Voting Registration Report, San Francisco and Marin (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Voting Registration Report, San Jose (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Voting Registration Report, San Mateo (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Work Diary, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Misc. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1940-49 (Box 2 (legal), Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1950-59 (Box 2 (legal), Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1960-69 (Box 2 (legal), Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1970-79 (Box 2 (legal), Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1980-89 (Box 2 (legal), Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 2 (legal), Folder 6)
  - "Doctor of la Huelga," 1968 (Box 2 (legal), Folder 7)
  - News clippings about Fred W. Ross (Box 2 (legal), Folder 8)
  - Scroll of Appreciation from CSO chapters, 1958 (Box 2 (legal), Folder 9)
  - Stickers and Buttons (Box 2 (legal), Folder 10)
  - Travel Reports (Box 2 (legal), Folder 11)
  - Travel Reports and Expenses (Box 2 (legal), Folder 12)
  - "Donde Nacen las Culturas," memento from the Guadalupe Organization, Incorporated, 1970 (Box 3 (OS))
- Series B. Subject Files (7 linear feet)
  This contains materials from organizations Ross worked with and subjects in which he was interested. Also included are two boxes of press clippings. The final part of the series consists of materials Ross used to train labor and community organizers. Larger items in this series were placed in legal size boxes and follow the regular sized items.
  - Subseries: Alphabetical by Subject
    - "Aboriginal Cultures of the Western Hemisphere," Golden Gate International Exposition, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Adult Education Association (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - AFL-CIO (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Agricultural Workers Organizing Committee (AWOC) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Saul Alinsky (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Alzheimer's Disease (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Amnesty International (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Paul C. Ashton, "The New World Society, Jehovah's Witnesses," 1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Asociación Nacional Mexicana Americana (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - California Attorney General, "Know your rights...when you buy on time" [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - California Center for Community Development (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - California Division of Fair Employment Practices, "Californians of Spanish Surname..." 1964 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - California Federation for Civic Unity (CFCU) (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Cesar Chavez for Governor Committee (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Citizens' Crusade Against Poverty (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Citizens for Farm Labor (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - City College Cooperative Education Newsletter, 1972, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Community Action Training Center (CATC) (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Conference on Community Relations, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Cooperation in Agriculture, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Corporación Organizada Para Acción y Servidora (COPAS) (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - CSO (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - CSO (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - CSO (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - CSO (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - CSO (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - CSO (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - CSO-- Alameda County (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - CSO-- Boyle Heights (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - CSO-- CIO, 1948-53 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - CSO-- Civil Rights Prior to 1950 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - CSO-- Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - CSO-- Educationals, San Jose (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - CSO-- Executive Board, Minutes, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - CSO-- Executive Committee, Minutes, 1949-50 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - CSO-- Executive Commitee, Minutes, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - CSO-- General Membership, Minutes, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - CSO-- Hanford (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - CSO-- Labor Commissioner (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - CSO-- LA (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - CSO-- LA (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - CSO-- Lincoln Heights (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - CSO-- Lincoln Heights [?] (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - CSO-- Membership, 1961-62 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - CSO-- National Conference of Christians and Jews, Inc., 1949-1953 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - CSO-- Neighborhood Matters (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - CSO-- News Releases (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - CSO-- Notes [1958?] (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - CSO-- Press Clippings (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - CSO-- Robert Marshall Fund, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - CSO-- San Bernardino (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - CSO-- San Jose (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - CSO-- Soledad (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - CSO-- Stockton (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - CSO-- Third National Convention, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Jeanne Davis, "Organizing the Urban Poor..." 1967 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Delano (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - "A Diocese Decides to Act," 1965 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Dan Dodson, "Power as a dimension of education," 1963 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - East Coast Migrant Health Project (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Economic Notes, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - "Exitos de Martinez Gil," 1955 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Farm Worker/Dept. of Employment Notices (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Farm Worker Legislation, Spanish version (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Friedland and Melkin, Migrant (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Varden Fuller, "A New Era for Farm Labor," Industrial Relations, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Ernesto Galarza, Strangers in Our Fields, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Gallo Boycott Songs (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Rodolfo Gonzalez, I am Joaquin, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Richard Griswold del Castillo (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Guadalupe, Arizona, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Guadalupe Organization, Inc. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Guadalupe Organization, Inc., "Donde Nacen las Culturas" [memento] (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Warren Hagstrom (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Warren Hagstrom, "Action Organizations of Minority Group Communities," 1965 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Warren Hagstrom, "CATC Notes," 1966 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Warren Hagstrom, "The Moral Case Against Social Action," 1965 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Warren Hagstrom, "The Organizer," 1965 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Warren Hagstrom, Poverty and Adult Education, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Warren Hagstrom, "Poverty and Adult Education," 1964 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Warren Hagstrom, "Poverty Planning," 1965 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Warren Hagstrom, "The Power of the Poor," 1964 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Warren Hagstrom, "A Preliminary Report on Social Action Problems" [n.d.] (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Warren Hagstrom, "Turn Back the Clock!" 1966 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Warren Hagstrom, "The View From the Office in Back," 1966 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Industrial Areas Foundation (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Industrial Areas Foundation (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "Interracial Prejudices in San Jose, California - 1950" (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - "Issei, Nisei, Kibei. Fortune Magazine..." 1944 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Vera Johnson, "The Teamsters" (song) (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Clark S. Knowlton, "Problems and Difficulties in Planning and Development in Areas with Large Minority Groups," 1964 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - "The Legend of Pancho Sanchez" (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Jacques E. Levy, "Cesar Chavez. Autobiography of La Causa," 1974 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - McFarland Cancer Cluster (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Mendota, California (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Mike Miller Class Outline (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Milligan (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Minimum Wage (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - MIT paper (poem about Chavez) (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - National Advisory Committee on Farm Labor (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - National Farm Worker Ministry (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - National Farm Workers Service Center (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Nuclear Weapons Freeze Campaign (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Orange County Segregated School Case (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - ORGANIZE, San Francisco (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Organizing materials (without organization names) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Tiberio Panzini, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Pax Americas (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Proposed Free Elections Law for Farm Workers [UFW?] (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Proposition 14, The Farm Labor Initiative (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Publications by AFL-CIO and other unions (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Earl Raab and Hugh Folk, "The Pattern of Dependent Poverty in (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - California," 1963 (Box 8)
    - Rancho Furukawa (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Sandra Rifkin, "Moving Cities. A Proposal for Migrant Farm Labor" (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Fred W. Ross Farmworkers Education Center (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Edward R. Roybal, speech on Communist Control Ordinance, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Rules of Order (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - San Diego Unity League (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Songs (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Spanish-language poetry and songs (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Staff List (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Stockton (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Stockton [?] (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Strike Song (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Syracuse University, "Proposal for a Community Development...Project," 1964 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Paul Taylor, Statement to Senate Committee, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Teamsters (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Teamsters (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Tolstoy Foundation (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - UAW Song Book (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - UFW (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - UFW 1976, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - UFW-- Agreement with Teamsters, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - UFW-- A & P Boycott, Cleveland, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - UFW--Benefit Fiesta Program, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - UFW-- Boycott, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - UFW-- California Agricultural Labor Relations Board, 1975-76 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - UFW-- El Malcriadito, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - UFW-- El Malcriado, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - UFW-- News Conference, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - UFW-- The Robert F. Kennedy Farm Worker Medical Plan (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - UFW-- Spanish manuscript fragment (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - UFW-- Training, Los Angeles, October 1974 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - UFW Chronological History (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - UFW Education Center (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - UFW history, "Our Long March," mss. [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - UFW history, Spanish-language interview of Ross, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - UFW Service Center material (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Urban Renewal [Lincoln Heights CSO?] (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Manuel Veiga, Guadalupe, Arizona (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - War Relocation Authority, 1945-46 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - War Relocation Authority, Cleveland (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - War Relocation Authority employment papers (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - War Relocation Authority, San Francisco, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - James Watson and Julian Samora, "Subordinate Leadership in a Bicultural Community..." American Sociological Review, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Woodville Farm Workers, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Irvin and Marilyn Yalom, "Ernest Hemingway - A Psychiatric View," 1971 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Youth Welfare Committee, 1952-53 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Affidavit forms (Box 10 (legal), Folder 1)
    - AFL-CIO Convention, 1968 (Box 10 (legal), Folder 2)
    - Saul Alinsky (Box 10 (legal), Folder 3)
    - Applications for work (Box 10 (legal), Folder 4)
    - Samuel Berger, Dollar Harvest (excerpt) (Box 10 (legal), Folder 5)
    - Buena Vista Labor Camp, 1960 (Box 10 (legal), Folder 6)
    - California Department of Motor Vehicles (Box 10 (legal), Folder 7)
    - California Federation for Civic Unity, 1949-53 (Box 10 (legal), Folder 8)
    - Chavez poster (Box 10 (legal), Folder 9)
    - Community Action Training Center (CATC) (Box 10 (legal), Folder 10)
    - CSO (Box 10 (legal), Folder 11)
    - CSO (Box 10 (legal), Folder 12)
    - CSO (Box 10 (legal), Folder 13)
    - CSO (Box 10 (legal), Folder 14)
    - CSO (Box 10 (legal), Folder 15)
    - CSO (Box 10 (legal), Folder 16)
    - CSO (Box 11 (legal), Folder 1)
    - CSO (Box 11 (legal), Folder 2)
    - CSO (Box 11 (legal), Folder 3)
    - CSO (Box 11 (legal), Folder 4)
    - CSO (Box 11 (legal), Folder 5)
    - CSO (Box 11 (legal), Folder 6)
    - CSO (Box 11 (legal), Folder 7)
    - CSO (Box 11 (legal), Folder 8)
    - CSO (Box 11 (legal), Folder 9)
    - CSO (Box 11 (legal), Folder 10)
    - CSO (Box 11 (legal), Folder 11)
    - CSO (Box 11 (legal), Folder 12)
    - Estimate of Mexican-American Voting Strength [n.d.] (Box 11 (legal), Folder 13)
    - Farm Labor File (Box 11 (legal), Folder 14)
    - Feinstein (Box 11 (legal), Folder 15)
    - Guadalupe, Arizona (Box 11 (legal), Folder 16)
    - Hearing, 1975 (Box 11 (legal), Folder 17)
    - Dolores Huerta [?] (Box 11 (legal), Folder 18)
    - L.A. County Committee on Human Relations, 1948-1953 (Box 11 (legal), Folder 19)
    - Mexican Council for Spanish-Speaking People, 1951-53 (Box 11 (legal), Folder 20)
    - National Campaign for Agricultural Democracy (Box 11 (legal), Folder 21)
    - National Farm Workers Association (Box 12 (legal), Folder 1)
    - "Notes from the Midwest Boycott Conference," 1975 (Box 12 (legal), Folder 2)
    - Organizing Materials (without organization names) (Box 12 (legal), Folder 3)
    - People's War Council Against Poverty (Box 12 (legal), Folder 4)
    - Phone List (Box 12 (legal), Folder 5)
    - Safeway (Box 12 (legal), Folder 6)
    - Songs (Box 12 (legal), Folder 7)
    - Statement by Cesar Chavez and Dolores Huerta to a Senate Subcommittee, 1969 (Box 12 (legal), Folder 8)
    - Marion Steeg, "Community Organizing Through Fund Raising," 1974 (Box 12 (legal), Folder 9)
    - Stockton, CA [1958] (Box 12 (legal), Folder 10)
    - Student Organization (Box 12 (legal), Folder 11)
    - Students for Kennedy (Box 12 (legal), Folder 12)
    - Syracuse (Box 12 (legal), Folder 13)
    - Table Grapes (Box 12 (legal), Folder 14)
    - UFW (Box 12 (legal), Folder 15)
    - UFW (Box 12 (legal), Folder 16)
    - UFW (Box 12 (legal), Folder 18)
    - UFW (Box 13 (legal), Folder 1)
    - UFW (Box 13 (legal), Folder 2)
    - UFW (Box 13 (legal), Folder 3)
    - UFW (Box 13 (legal), Folder 4)
    - UFW-- Agreement with Paul Masson, 1976 (Box 13 (legal), Folder 5)
    - UFW-- Collective Bargaining Agreement, InterHarvest, 1970 (Box 13 (legal), Folder 6)
    - UFW-- El Malcriado, 1974 (Box 13 (legal), Folder 7)
    - UFW-- El Mosquito Zumbador, 1966 and n.d. (Box 13 (legal), Folder 8)
    - UFW-- Leaflets (Box 13 (legal), Folder 9)
    - Misc. (Box 13 (legal), Folder 10)
  - Subseries: Press Clippings
    - Newspaper Clippings-- 1941 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper Clippings-- 1948 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper Clippings-- 1953 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper Clippings-- 1954 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper Clippings-- 1955 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper Clippings-- 1958 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper Clippings-- 1960 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper Clippings-- 1962 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper Clippings-- 1965 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper Clippings-- 1966 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper Clippings-- 1967 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper Clippings-- 1968 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper Clippings-- 1969 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper Clippings-- 1970 (Box 14, Folder 14)